it's almost
2025 and you are still not profitable
and you want to become a Trader this is
either the beginning of your story or
the end of your trading Journey if what
I'm about to say inside this video makes
sense and you like it it's good that
means that it's meant for you but if it
doesn't and you don't get it you're
pretty much [__] so the blueprint on
how to become a profitable Trader so I
want to give you guys some context on
what Prof profitability even is let me
make it extremely clear that being a
profitable Trader is not having a
Lamborghini or having gold chains or
grills in your mouth or Gucci shoes that
does not mean that you're a profitable
Trader that just means that you're
honestly a douchebag a profitable Trader
is somebody that makes money on top of
the money that they started on their
trading account the best traders in the
world the most legendary Traders known
in history someone like waren Buffett
make anywhere from 12 to about
19.8% annually now I want you guys to
realize what that is monthly because 12
to 19% annually might seem like a decent
amount of return but when you look at it
in retrospect on a monthly basis he is
making anywhere from 1 to
1.6% average a month a Trader that makes
1% to 1.6% a month is a profitable
Trader take this from The Legend like
somebody like Warren Buffett Warren
Buffett is a profitable Trader by simply
making 1% a month now if you're a Trader
right now and you're making 50% a month
and you still don't think you're
profitable well you are not only a
lunatic but you're making a big mistake
it's not about making a [__] ton of
percentage or making a [__] ton of money
it's about making consistent gains
trading is like a Marathon you are here
for the long run you're not here for the
short-term gains and the quick Sprints
that is not how you become a profitable
Trader that's just how you make money in
the markets making money is going in and
out and then you don't ever really come
back and you treat it like a hobby if
you're ready to make trading your main
source of income and even replace your
current income it has to be passion it
has to be something that you do every
single day with love and care and you do
it forever you don't do it just for a
week a month or even a year when you
become a Trader it is literally for life
so now that you have some context on
what a actual profitable Trader is and
that it is basically a percentage game
and making as small as 1% on your
account monthly or heck even quarterly
makes you a profitable Trader I want to
get into the first step on what is going
to be key for you to be consistently
profitable in the markets and make these
percentages on top of your account every
single month the first one is going to
be stop catching a falling knife and
stop trying to stop a rocket if a knife
is falling and you go and grab it what's
going to happen you're going to cut your
hand because it's sharp and as soon as
you grab it with the momentum it's going
to slice your fingers or maybe one of
ilam mus SpaceX rockets that is taken
off going to the Mars you're not going
to stop that that basically makes no
sense you don't want to go against the
momentum if the market is going up or if
the market is going that if you try and
predict the bottom of a market you're
going to literally lose every single
time and if you're going to predict the
top of a market you're going to lose
every single time what makes more sense
if a knife is falling to just continue
to push it down and if a rocket is going
up to continue to push it up or
completely go against the force that
it's doing obviously it makes more sense
to go with the momentum it's the exact
same thing in the markets you do not
want to trade against the trend if the
market is going down continue to sell
with the market going down if the market
is going up continue to buy with the
market going up this is such a simple
concept and once I truly understood this
I not only started to make so much more
money with my trading but I started to
avoid all of the small losses that
contined to eat up the profits that I
was having I was understanding the
markets I was predicting what what they
were going to do but I was still taking
these little degenerate trades and that
I was going to be the person that
predicted the top and I got the sniper
entry or I predicted the bottom and I
got the perfect entry like if that was
going to make me profitable being a
profitable Trader is not predicting the
bottoms or the highs it's about making a
logical trading decision that is going
to make you money on the long run and me
catching these types of Trades actually
was doing more negative to my trading
than positive because I was losing more
times every single time I would take it
and every loss that I would take it
would affect my psychology for the next
trade that I would take so catching a
falling knife is never the solution and
you guys know Elon you don't want to go
against anything that he's doing and
catching a falling knife or trying to
stop a rocket which is where you're
trying to predict the top of the market
or predict the bottom of the market it's
where you're trying to be right it's
like you're trying to prove a point that
you can predict that okay it's going to
turn around from here and it's going to
stop here like that's such an ego move
and that is not going to make you
profitable making profitable is not on
what you think or what you want to
happen what is going to happen is the
trend is going to continue going in the
direction that it's going to go and the
trend is your friend you're going to
make money by following the trend not
going against it and trust me I've been
there a million times where I've
predicted the bottom or I predicted the
top and it feels good you feel like the
top G but trading is not about feeling
good it's not about what you want it's
about the correct thing that you're
going to do in the markets to be
profitable do you think Warren Buffett
does things to feel good for all of his
investors around the world [__] no he
does the right thing to make money and
become and stay a profitable Trader and
this takes me to step number two which
goes perfectly hand inand which is the
Holy Grail trade the trade that I need
to make this money I need to make back
the losses that I have in the market I
need to end off the week in profits
because I have a bill to pay at the end
of this week or at the end of the month
guys I get it everybody goes into
trading with a different financial
situation everybody goes in by wanting
to make money or needing to make money
there's people out there that get into
trading that really really really really
need the money and the money that they
invest into trading they are not willing
to lose and honestly they can't even
afford it and if you're someone out
there like that or remotely close to
that you should not even start to trade
because trading will take every single
dollar away from you because it is
literally based off of risk and some
people just don't know how to calculate
that risk and these traders that need
that money they're going to constantly
look for a trade so they can have that
money a holy Grill trade I want to take
these 50 bucks into 200 so I can pay the
life bill at the the end of the month or
just because I want to do it and this is
not trading this is gambling this is not
the way on how you're going to be a
profitable Trader and how you're going
to be a consistent Trader now don't get
me wrong flipping accounts and growing
small amounts of money is fun I've done
it before I've turned 100 bucks into a
mill I've taken plenty of 10K accounts
to six figures and yes I get it it looks
cool it looks fun it gets you excited
but I do that now because it is
something that I do to entertain myself
and just challenge myself but I don't
rely on this as my income from trade
it's just a challenge that I set for
myself and entertain the trading
Community with but for you to be a
profitable Trader do not strive to make
this your main source of income from
Trading that you're going to look for
this holy Grill trade that you're going
to go all in right now and you're going
to make this trade make back your losses
and put you on top ch facing that
feeling is going to put you in such a
deep hole that is never going to give
you the clarity of the mind that you
need to have to actually take the right
trade that is actually going to make you
those profits that type of trade happens
when you're trading plan checks out not
when you want to go and take that trade
and make it happen the market does not
care if you're in depth the market does
not care if you need the money market
does not care how much you've lost how
much time you've been in front of it the
market doesn't even know you exist so
don't take your emotions into something
that absolutely has no context on who
you are and what you're going through
make it strictly about business and
about a logical trading decision this
holy Grill trade and I need this money
is not the way on how you're going to
become a profitable Trader trading is to
be treated as a business you have to be
passionate about it and you have to be
ready to give a 100% every single day
until you truly understand the craft the
Holy Grail the jackpot trade yes it is a
possibility it is there you can get that
type of trade and it could happen to
everybody watching this video but it's
not sustainable and I would not go about
your trading every single day looking
for this trade for this jackpot trade
this 10x 20x trade it might be cool it
might be fun but I would not rely on
this and I will give you my word on this
if you stick around in trading long
enough
plenty of those trades will come and I
want to make something very clear on why
this is not sustainable personally
myself I like to consider myself U I'm a
very Advanced Trader I don't want to
consider myself an expert yet I want to
have a decade into the market and then
I'll call myself an expert but even
myself when I tried to turn the 100
bucks into the mill it took me about a
year and a half to complete it I blew
plenty of challenges with it and even
when I'm turning these 10K into six
figures I am blowing these accounts all
of the time because again this is
something that I do because I accept the
risk behind it and I okay with the
outcome if I lose cool if I win cool
it's just a certain amount of money that
I am okay with losing and this is
something that is going to happen to
every single Trader even if it's the
Warr and buffets of the world because
there's no such thing as 100% win rate
90% win rate 70% win rate I am a
profitable Trader and I successfully
have turned the 100 bucks into a million
with a 65 to 60% win rate you do not
need anything more than that and it is
not going to change anything you're
trading if you have a higher win rate
because the risk reward is key more
about that later in the video so you
know now not to rely on this holy Grill
trade but what you do need to rely on is
my third step and it's going to be a
profitable and a winning strategy this
is going to be key for you to know
exactly what you're going to do every
single day when you go to the markets
and this goes with the third point which
is do not get distracted with the shiny
object syndrome I am a victim of it all
of my Trader friends are victim of it
plenty of Traders inside of my community
are a victim of it many of us get click
baited into following a certain strategy
because that mentor on that given day
has made x amount of money and if you
want to learn from them go and join
their program immediately so you can
have the same type of results what ends
up happening is you either join the
program and it's not good or you just
don't give it enough time for it to work
see somebody else posting great results
have the same message you join the
program and now you have to completely
switch your narrative from one to
another and then you're just constantly
hopping from different programs
different strategies just because on a
specific day where the other strategy
made no money this new strategy now made
money and you think this is going to be
the solution to your problem losing is
going to be part of trading you're
putting something at risk every single
time you go into into the market it is a
risk to reward business you give
something to potentially get something
in return now what you put at risk is
very pre-calculated and you know exactly
how much you're going to lose and now
the reward when you come back you
measure it before you take the risk
there is no strategy out there that is
going to take that risk away so whenever
you lose with a specific strategy or
things aren't going as you planned don't
switch to a different strategy like if
that's going to be the solution to your
problem that is literally going to
change nothing if anything that's
actually going to put you deeper into
the hole simply because you have not
given the actual strategy that you're
learning at that very moment enough time
for it to play out and you even fully
understand it you also have to be very
aware the market moves in Cycles how the
market moved in the first 3 months of
the year is not the same way it's going
to move in the last 3 months of the year
q1 Q2 Q3 and Q4 are all very much
different and if you have a specific
specific strategy in q1 and then another
strategy in Q2 and another strategy in
Q3 and another strategy in Q4 you're
basically back at square zero because
when the market goes back to then
January back in q1 you haven't done
anything you have no history you have no
practice you have no knowledge do not
get the shiny object syndrome and
whenever you're going through whatever
in your trading Journey Don't Look for
ways to add something or remove
something losing is part of the game the
most important thing is that you
pre-calculate that risk very
strategically and you are okay with it
don't constantly try and cover up a loss
with an excuse or with a potential
different solution it is not the
solution to your case now when you find
that strategy and you start coming back
from those losses you're going to
obviously win because when you get
involved into the market two things are
going to happen Market's either going to
go up or it's going to go down it's a
50/50 it's pretty [__] damn hard to
not even see some type of profit at one
given point at a time right you're going
to see some blues at some point even if
you don't know anything about trading
you click the right or wrong button
sometimes you're going to see some blues
for sure Reds but you will see some
blues now when you do see those Blues
this takes me to the next point it's
going to be don't get obsessed with the
blues don't think that now because you
got it you can't let it go or you let it
go too soon so the next next point that
I want to talk about is not set and
forgetting enough or set and forgetting
too much because this is going to be the
actual Secret Sauce of you becoming a
profitable Trader and I really did not
realize this until about 2 and a half
years into my trading journey I was
predicting the market all the time I
knew exactly if it was going to go up or
go down I knew when to enter I knew
where to place my take profit I knew
where to put my stop loss but my issue
was when I enter a trade I would wait 3
days if it's in draw down because I did
never ever wanteded to close the trade
in a loss even if it was floating inside
of my stop loss for 3 days I would hold
it no issue because all I wanted to do
was for it to go back into profit or
break even and I would get out
immediately and guess what would happen
after I would do that the trade would
fly to my takeprofit what was I doing I
wasn't set and forgetting enough
okay I crossed over that hurdle I let
the trades play out I let the trade
either hit my stop loss or get to my
takeprofit and when trades started
getting to my takeprofit I was like you
know what I'm the [__] I want to make
more money and I was continue to hold
trades past my takeprofit and guess what
ended up happening the trade would
reverse all the way back into my entry
level or even go to my stop loss so I
let a winning trade turn into a losing
trade so now at this point I had extreme
frustration because I am predicting the
market and now I am sometimes holding
too much in the stop- loss or holding
too much in the takeprofit OR holding
not enough inside of the takeprofit for
me to actually close out and make some
profits now at this point I know it's
not me analyzing the markets I know it's
not the strategy it's me I'm not set and
forgetting enough or I'm set and
forgetting too much and this is what
held me back from becoming a profitable
Trader for the course of 6 months me
realizing that when the trade gets to my
take profit you close it and that is it
you do not [__] with the trade in
between if the trade is in draw down you
let it to be if your trade is on the way
to take profit you let it be if your
trade hits stop loss you move on if your
trade hits take profit you move on
there's only four different scenarios
that are going to happen and those are
them now you don't do anything in
between you're only going to do two
things with your trade one close out of
your stop loss or two close out of your
take profit don't go to break even you
don't tra your stop losses you don't do
any of that [__] all that does is mess
with your risk to reward on the trade
that you're taking you take a trade you
accept the risk you win or you lose
period and where you truly truly truly
become a hyper successful Trader and you
start having results like mine is where
you find the perfect balance in between
both closing out at your take profit and
strategically setting and forgetting
through your take profit now this is
something that I don't recommend
beginner traders to do right off the bat
this is something that takes time and
this something that I recommend people
to test on a different account aside
from your main one this is something
that you have to get used to doing first
and you have to really understand how to
do it technically wise because if you
start to practice it on your main
account where you're actually making
money
you're basically messing with your
emotions and with the potential profits
you're going to have at that very point
I don't recommend you do it with demo
because I don't think anything in demo
is real and I don't think that the
emotions and the type of way you're
going to react in demo is ever the same
I think you should just do it on a
smaller account so for example let's say
you have a $10,000 personal account
that's where you're making your majority
of your income from Trading and you want
to test out new things on holding trades
past your takeprofit or closing them at
certain point
you do that with a $100 account so it's
live money it's real and you get to see
the outcome happen with real money that
is yours and you have access to it
immediately if you were to want to but
if it's not going good or you're kind of
learning it and you haven't figured it
out yet well it's only with a small
account and it's not messing with the
actual profits that you have in your
personal account this is key to scaling
your trading to the next level set and
forgetting too much is not good and not
set and forgetting is also not good
finding the perfect balance is where
your deep deep success lies and that
basically lays it up for my next topic
which is going to be be real with
yourself guys when I was working at
Dunkin Donuts do you think I was telling
myself tomorrow we are making
$100,000 well yes I'm not going to lie I
said that to myself and guess what
happened that did not happen I never
made $100,000 on the next day or the
next week or the next month because I
was not meant for that I was not built
for that at that that very moment I was
not being real with myself I wanted that
money because I'm a young 18 19 20 year
old in Miami seeing all this crazy
lavish lifestyle and I want it but I am
barely making $2 $3,000 a month what
lets me think that I am qualified to
have access to six figures at that very
moment absolutely nothing I am not
qualified to have six figures either in
my savings in my checkings in credit I
don't have I I I'm not qualified for
that I have not built the resume I don't
have the character I don't have the
experience at that point in time you
would have gave me that money I would
have blown it because I would have not
known what to do with it I was not being
real with myself and that's what happens
with a lot of you guys right now you
start seeing all of these other Traders
online making a [__] ton of money
supposedly and you want to have the same
thing but you want to have the same
thing without doing what they did to get
to that point you're jealous of the
results but not of the journey that they
had to go through to get to those
results and that's exactly what happened
to me and I only had to go through about
a, losses for me to realize that hey you
know what let me just start off with
making my first $10 let me start off
with making my first hundred then my
first th000 then my first 5,000 10,000
20 to then where I eventually got to the
point where I made 100,000 but it took
me a lot of losses for me to realize
that you know what Alex let's just be
real with yourself let's do what you're
ready to do if I make $10 today or if I
lose them today it probably won't affect
me it's not a big deal and I am going to
build that character with time where
then I'm going to continuously raise
that bar higher and higher and higher to
where then I am able to do that but you
have to create the foundation by being
real with yourself don't set unrealistic
take profits and because you don't get
to them you start to beat yourself up
that I think is a bit low and honestly
it just shuts down your self-esteem and
it's not going to help you beating
yourself up for something that you know
deep deep deep deep down that you won't
be able to achieve it in a certain
timeline I think it's a bit douchy
honestly like it's going to be an excuse
that you're going to use to not continue
continue to go forward set a realistic
goal be real with yourself and just
because you don't reach it don't let it
be an excuse to quit and I've heard this
many times before from a lot of traders
that they say if I don't become
profitable by January of next year I'm
going to quit and I'm like well dude you
just might as well quit right now
because you're not being real with
yourself why should you be profitable by
January of next year are you going to
put in the 10,000 hours are you going to
watch all of the videos you should watch
are you going to put in the Thousand
trades are you going to put in your own
real like there's so many things that
have to get done in order for you to
become profitable you can't just make a
wish and then it magically happened you
have to put in the work first and I
would put the goal that you want to
achieve and then let time do its thing
and something to just add or maybe even
sprinkle on top of all of this is when
you want to get these tangible things
right the cars the watches the lifestyle
the luxury it's all cool but again it's
all just a materialistic thing at the
end of the day I'm sure you guys have
seen I could care less about any of my
super cars I have a a Lamborghini that
just caught fire I have a Porsche that
I've blown the transmission three times
I have a drift car that I have destroyed
at 10 times like none of these
materialistic things mean anything or I
going to Define who you are it's the
journey that you're going to go go
through that is going to Define who you
are and then normalize all of these
materialistic things that you want what
is going to get you these materialistic
things is not the urge for wanting them
it's for the journey that you go through
that is going to give you the success to
just make these things fall in your lap
I at one point I really wanted to have a
fleet of supercars and even when I
became a profitable Trader that I was
making money over and over and over
every single month and I'm constantly
having profits and flipping accounts and
scaling I didn't really have a fleet of
supercars until about 5 years into my
trading Journey until I was a whole 2
and 1/2 years now profitable I'm talking
about 2 and 1/2 Years Learning and 2 and
1/2 years profitable now is when all of
these cars are just falling on my lap
and I'm buying them like if they were a
pair of shoes and I kind of had a
reality check the other day and it was
like wow I remember when I was making
money as I started trading I really
wanted all these cars but I just wasn't
making enough money trading to afford
all of them and now it's at the point
where I don't even care about them I'm
getting them all by accident I'm buying
them just adding them to the car and
they just get shipped to my house and
when they get here I'm like ah I liked
more when I was actually working to get
to that point and enjoying the journey
so you will get those materialistic
things that you want but you're not
going to get it by just wanting them
you're going to get it by going through
the Journey to actually get them and
believe me when I say this at the end of
the day when you're sitting in the lambo
in traffic at a red light with a bunch
of NPCs you're going to enjoy more the
journey that got you to that Lambo and
actually driving the lambo but not right
away probably a year after you have it
but you'll get there soon don't even
worry about it and lastly and most
definitely not least probably one of my
favorite topics in order for things in
your life to change you have to change
things in your life and truthfully this
kind of quote that I personally think I
am the founder of it I believe or I
could be totally [__] wrong I really
put it into test about a couple weeks
ago where I bumped into one of my high
school colleagues that I had a couple
years ago at a gas station and I open
the door to this gas station and I am a
gentleman and I let the person that's
going to walk out walk out and then I
walk in get my snack put gas and then
leave and as I open the door the person
that is standing right in front of me is
all dirty and a mechanic gear and
basically looks really bad and fat and
I'm like sir like are you going to get
out and he's like Alex and I'm like oh
[__] I I I don't know who the [__] this
is and I look up and I'm like holy [__]
I'm not going to say his name but I'm
like dude I Remember You from High
School what's up bro start talking for a
couple of minutes and he like in his
eyes he had like these like tears right
like he he didn't want to cry but like I
saw his eyes get watery and he's like
look bro I'm just very happy for you bro
I see so many things that have changed
in your life and I just wanted to say I
wish I did what you did I am a mechanic
right now I have two kids with two
different baby mamas I am working two
jobs mechanic and ubering and I could
barely make it and I wish I would have
changed my habits early on than what I
decided to just be comfortable and
continue to stay how I was he was still
smoking weed he was still hanging around
with the same people and he was
literally not doing anything productive
and it got him to a point where now he
is basically stuck he feels like he
cannot get out of that and he definitely
can but in his mind he feels like he
[__] up for life and he's done but he
got to that point because the foundation
that he created in high school when he
was smoking weed and being with the
people that he wasn't supposed to be he
is now still in there because he never
changed things in his life so his
results never changed I wasn't around
the best people in high school but I
wasn't around the worst either and I was
skipping school I was smoking weed I was
doing dumb stuff and when I left High
School I realized that hey things in my
life have to change and in order for
that I have to change things in my life
I cut out the bad friends I cut out
doing irresponsible things stop smoking
weed stop drinking stopped doing nothing
that didn't do me any better and guess
what happened things in my life changed
because I changed things in my life and
after I had a 5minute conversation with
this guy I basically gave him some tips
and stuff but what I really really
embedded into his head was like look bro
if you want things in your life to
change stop doing the same [__] and
I saw him walking out of the gas station
with these Rock papers which are things
where you're going to break up the weed
and smoke it and I'm like dude like
you're still doing the same [__] like is
it worth getting high for 30 minutes and
just watching Netflix and getting hungry
and he looks at me he's like bro you
know what it's not and he got it and he
threw it away now I don't know if
tomorrow is going to go and buy it again
or do whatever but at least he did a
small start to get started and that's I
feel like off somebody needs to really
get that fire in them fueled up so they
can start having this Compound Effect
for positivity and start changing things
in your life when people start going
downhill they go downhill really fast
like they start getting into one thing
and that leads to another and another
and another but that also happens uphill
and the momentum uphill is actually a
lot better because you start not only
changing yourself but your surroundings
and the people around from you so you
know something that's small like that I
I realize it it could have changed his
whole entire day maybe his whole entire
week and month and I hope to bump into
him soon and he's doing something
different but the foundation is built by
if you want for things in your life to
change you have to change things in your
life and truthfully if you can have one
takeaway from all of these different
tips that I gave you inside of this I
would say this last one is by far the
most important and I hate to mention
this right now because really I'm not
the type of guy that's like yo my
program is the bad or my it's it's
really not like I I really hate to say
this but like I have literally taking
people that know absolutely nothing from
Trading and have nowhere to start to
going to making the first 5 10 15K in a
month in the first year of trading
inside of my program I have a psychology
series and I just say this because I've
never talked about it I have a
psychology series that I created when I
was in my upcoming years as a Trader
like literally when you see the videos
you see alexg in 2020 2021 and you see
this kid that he is literally having
that breakthrough like you can see it in
his eyes that he has he just figured
this [__] out he knows what to do he
just knows he has to do it for a little
bit more time and he's going to start
having results and I've tried to
recreate these videos before and make
them you know a lot more higher
production in a better scenario but it's
just not authentic it's not real like I
cannot even if I were to just write down
everything I said in those videos and
replicate it it won't come out the same
because I just am in a different head
space right now like I can take you from
from level 100 to 1,000 right now with
my psychology but the videos inside of
my program literally will take you from
0 to 100 because I am inside of this
beginner Trader that is cracking out of
a shell and I just happen to be very
fortunate to have documented all of
those different videos showcasing what
I'm learning practicing and teaching to
people all around the world so if you
guys want to know more about my
psychology series or the actual seven
forget program that you know takes
Traders all around the world to get the
first thousand to $1,500 a week make
sure you guys check out the link in the
description below it is there for you
guys a video that explains absolutely
everything and I hope to see you guys
inside or in another one of my videos
make sure to hit that like And subscribe
button if you guys like these type of
videos let me know as well in the
comments below because it keeps me
motivated keeps me going to doing them
and truthfully if you like it I'll even
do another one even deeper taking guys
from 100 to 1,000 thank you guys very
much and I'll see you guys in the next
one